Vitor Cesco

Senior iOS Engineer

vitorcesco.com vitorcesco@me.com +55 12988580858 SP - Brazil

Summary

Engineering applications since the dawn of the AppStore, my 10+ years of experience on iOS range from building up emerging startups to contributing to giants of the aviation industry.

I'm a very communicative leader, passionate about Apple and all its legacy in our community.

Experience

Senior iOS Engineer

TheoremOne 07/2022 - Present

Senior iOS Engineer and Tech Lead

03/2021 - 06/2022

BairesDev

Leading a team of 5 iOS Developers in creating high-quality deliveries for a major medical company based on CA-USA.

Top of the line technologies such as Swift, SwiftU, CI/CD and automated testing were used to guarantee high standards.

Senior iOS Engineer

Turtle AI 10/2018 - 03/2021

Senior iOS developer working with Turtle, a development agency based in the US. Providing many startups around the world top level solutions in iOS.

On Turtle I've peen mostly working with a client called Marcel for Art. We've developed an iOS application focused on helping emerging artists manage their artwork inventory, as well as boost their online presence with media kit generation, online web galleries and shops.

The app was entirely built on Swift, SwiftUI, UIKit, with design guidelines coming from Figma deliveries.

I also participated on weekly design meetings, helping the designers think like a developer which helped a lot on reducing the "back and forth" a badly designed UI brings.

Senior iOS Engineer

Lets Events 07/2017 - 10/2018

Responsible for the development (from scratch using Swift) and maintenance of the Lets Events iOS application.

The app helped event admins to manage guests lists, as well as check them in. Local caching, REST, GraphQL and QR Code reading are a some of the challenges faced on this application.

I also have participation on the web application developed using React.

iOS and Web Front-end (React) Developer

Rolfson Oil 12/2016 - 07/2017

Developed and maintained iOS applications, including the migration of legacy code from Objective-C to Swift.

Development of new technologies using React, replacing the use of old enterprise softwares.

iOS and Web Full-Stack Developer

Tyton Holdings 12/2014 - 12/2016

Developed a total of 3 iOS apps, including universal binaries and Apple Watch extensions. Built from scratch libraries to maintain a good code practice. Created custom UI elements to achieve the brand visual identity, all of them based on native UIKit protocols to maintain maximum compatibility across all devices and future iOS updates.

On the web side, developed a total of 4 systems, 2 or them were simple PHiP prototypes and 2 were full Node.js web applications, which interact with all or the iOS apps. Front and Backend were architectured by me. Responsible for most of the coding, as well as revising and managing every pull request from other developers.

Lead iOS Developer

Embraer 01/2014 - 12/2014

Lead the iOS Development of the eQRH app, a huge project in partnership with Embraer, a major aircraft manufacturer from Brazil. Dealing with diversity and the need to comply with many exotic requirements from the engineers and board of pilots from Embraer was a huge challenge.

I was responsible for not only developing Objective-C code, but also reviewing code from third-party contractors, preparing and performing presentations and researching new technologies like offline speech recognition.

Education

Computer Engineering

UNITAU - Universidade de Taubaté

12/2014

Bachelor degree in Computer Engineering from UNITAU, with majors in Software Engineering and Artificial Intelligence.

Physics Scientific Initiation

ITA - Aerospace Technological Institute

12/2014

Projects and paper publications were related to the subject: Studying and Measuring Non-ionising Radiation on the Vale do Paraíba Region.

Skills

- ▶ iOS
 - Swift
 - SwiftUI
 - Universal Binaries (including MacOS)
 - Objective-C
 - TestFlight
 - AppStore Connect
 - Xcode Cloud

- ▶ General
 - Automated Testing
 - CI/CD
 - User Interface Design
 - Bluetooth
 - Arduino
 - Node.JS
 - ReactJS

Languages

- ► English (Fluent)
- ► Spanish (Moderate)
- ► Portuguese (Fluent)